Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo collection of New Mexico folklife documentation
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo collection of New Mexico folklife documentation 1976-1992 1984-1986
AFC 2022/001
Kalb, Laurie Beth
approximately 2,469 items
14 containers
23 sound cassettes: analog
1,283 slides: black and white, color; 35 mm
95 transparencies: color, positive; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in.
approximately 227 negative frames (in 43 strips): black and white, color; 35 mm
79 photographic prints: black and white; various sizes
45 photographic prints: color; various sizes
15 contact sheets: black and white
2 contact sheets: color
2 containers (10 linear inches)
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, and audio recordings related to the New Mexico Folklife Project collection (AFC 1991/032) collected in 1984 and 1985.
Provenance
Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo; Donation; 2022.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
New Mexico Folklife Project collection (AFC 1991/032). Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo participated in the New Mexico Folklife Project as one of the interviewers. As a result, this collection has some items that may be exact duplicates from the original project. There are a few items that are labelled "copy" but there are other items that are not associated with any related materials. At this time it is difficult to compare versions. Please note the following recordings (SR10, SR12-SR18, and SR23) may be exact duplicates to New Mexico Folklife Project collection recordings.
Online presentation: http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/collafc.afc1991032
Finding aid: https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af021003
Cosmo's original field documents and reports from the New Mexico Folklife Project collection are archived at the Museum of International Folk Art.
Access and Restrictions
The Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo collection of New Mexico folklife documentation is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo is currently a lecturer at the University of Leiden University Center for the Arts in Society in the Netherlands. Before relocating to Europe, Cosmo was a folklorist who worked as a curator and museum administrator at several institutions and was the recipient of a number of fellowships and a Fulbright award.
In the 1980s, she participated in two projects where she worked alongside Carl Fleischhauer and Boyd Pratt in New Mexico. Cosmo documented the art of Hispanic carvers in northern New Mexico while working on the New Mexico Folklife Project. A year later she contributed to the survey of historic architecture in the northeastern quadrant of New Mexico.
Cosmo authored two books from the project, Crafting Devotions: Tradition in Contemporary New Mexico Santos and Santos Statues & Sculpture: Contemporary Woodcarving from New Mexico.
Scope and Content
The collection includes manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, and audio recordings related to the New Mexico Folklife Project collection. Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo represented the Museum of International Folk Art (Santa Fe) on the project and conducted fieldwork with Carl Fleischhauer, consultant, of the American Folklife Center. This collection includes fieldwork related to Cosmo's M.A. (1985) and Ph.D. (1992) theses at the University of Pennsylvania and other projects.
Arrangement
The Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo collection of New Mexico folklife documentation is organized in 3 series. Materials are arranged alphabetically within Series 1, Subseries 1; and chronologically within the remainder of the series.
Series 1: Fieldwork
Series 2: Exhibitions
Series 3: Academic Works
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Kalb, Laurie Beth
Subjects
Folk art--New Mexico.; Hispanic American art--New Mexico.; Santos (Art)--New Mexico.; Vernacular architecture--New Mexico.
Places
New Mexico--Folklore.; New Mexico--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Articles.; Color slides.; Conference papers and proceedings.; Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Field notes.; Field recordings.; Interviews.; Photographs.
Container List
- Series 1: Fieldwork
  - Subseries 1: Field notes and correspondence
    - Teresa Archuleta-Sagel, August 10, 1983, AFC 2022/001: SR02; Weaver; 1 sound cassette
      Chimayo, New Mexico
    - Jose Benjamin Lopez (1/2), 1984-1992, manuscript materials, 8 black-and-white prints, and 1 color print (Box-folder 1/1)
      Includes interviews, correspondence, and articles pertaining to Lopez's life and his work in the Hispanic arts. His work was used in several exhibits and papers curated by Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo. There is also a handwritten log and accompanying photographic prints of the Lopez family displaying some of their art, July 13, 1984.
    - Jose Benjamin Lopez (2/2), 1984-1992, manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/2)
      Jose Benjamin Lopez field notes and correspondence.
    - Clayton cattle auction, August 28, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR12; Auctioneer; 1 sound cassette
      Billy Joe Wright recording with Carl Fleischhauer. This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr01.
    - Clayton cattle auction, August 28-29, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR13; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: NM85-LKR1 - NM85-LKR2, Bench tape.
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr01 and afc1991032_sr02.
    - Joe and Alissandra Cordova, August 29, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR14; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Mosquero, New Mexico side 1 and 2 (copied by LK in Sante Fe, New Mexico). Joe Cordova, Mosquero, New Mexico, Boyd Pratt and Laurie Kalb, interviewing from Nagra (A).
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr03.
    - Joe and Alissandra Cordova, August 29, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR15; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Mosquero, New Mexico, Boyd Pratt and Laurie Kalb interviewing from Nagra (B).
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr04.
    - Joe Cordova, August 29, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR16; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: NM85-LKR3/NM85-LKR4.
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr03 and afc1991032_sr04.
    - Joe Cordova and Enrique Sanchez, August 29, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR17; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: NM85-LKR6, NM85-LKR5.
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr05 and afc1991032_sr06.
    - Trinidad Garcia, August 22, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR10; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Erma's mother, Mosquero, New Mexico. BP and LK interview. Trinidad Garcia (Erma Trujillo's mother).
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr11.
    - Margarito and Trinidad Garcia, August 30, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR18; 1 sound cassette
      NM85-LKR7/NM85-LKR8/MN85-LKR8: The recordings are on two tapes.
      NM85-LKR7: Interview with Margarito Garcia and Trinidad Garcia about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985 (part 1 of 3).
      MN85-LKR8: Interview with Margarito Garcia and Trinidad Garcia about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985 (part 2 of 3).
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr07 and afc1991032_sr08.
    - Margarito and Trinidad Garcia, August 30, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR23; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: [Recording on one side.] NM85-LKR9-Copy
      NM85 LKR9: Interview with Margarito Garcia and Trinidad Garcia about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985 (part 3 of 3).
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr09.
    - Felix Lopez, June 22, 1984, AFC 2022/001: SR03; Santo maker; 1 sound cassette
      Santo making in New Mexico.
    - Luisito Lujan, 1984-1995, manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/3)
      Includes interview notes, newsletters and correspondence pertaining to his participation in the New Mexico Folklife Project and the "La Escuela Artesana:" Art from the Soul.
    - Luisito Lujan, July 17, 1984, AFC 2022/001: SR04; Santo maker; 1 sound cassette
      Santo maker in New Mexico.
    - Eulogio and Zoriada Ortega, 1984-1994, manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/4)
      Includes interviews and correspondence with Eulogio and Zoraida Ortega. They have participated in a few exhibits curated by Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo.
    - Enrique Rendon (1/2), 1984-1988, manuscript materials, 14 black-and-white prints (Box-folder 1/5)
      Includes interview with Enrique Rendon conducted in part with American Folklife Center. There are notepads of handwritten field notes along with transcripts, notes and a typed summary of the visit.
    - Enrique Rendon (2/2), 1984-1988, manuscript materials, 14 black-and-white prints (Box-folder 1/6)
      Includes interview of Enrique Rendon conducted in part with American Folklife Center. There are handwritten field notes and accompanying transcripts in notepads along with photographic prints.
    - Enrique Rendon, July 25, 1984, AFC 2022/001: SR06; Santo maker; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Velarde, New Mexico, Tape 1.
    - Enrique Rendon, July 25, 1984, AFC 2022/001: SR07; Santo maker; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Velarde, New Mexico, Tape 2.
    - Orlando Romero, July 28, 1983, AFC 2022/001: SR01; Santo maker; 1 sound cassette
      Interview was recorded in New Mexico.
    - Luis Tapia, 1984-1992, manuscript materials, 3 color contacts sheets (8 1/2 x 11); 1 photocopy black-and white-print (8 x 10); 32 color slides (35 mm); 1 color transparency (4 x 5); 2 color prints (4 x 6) (Box-folder 1/7)
      Includes handwritten and typed interview notes, along with correspondence, articles, by laws of a Hispanic arts association, and a dissertation chapter draft on Luis' work. It also includes the planning of the exhibit which Tapia participated in at the Owings-Dewey Fine Art Gallery. Tapia has also participated in a number of exhibitions curated by Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo. There are also photographic images of Tapia's work.
    - Luis Tapia, 1984-1992, manuscript materials, 19 color prints (3 1/2 x 5 1/2) (Box-folder 1/8)
      Includes interview with Luis Tapia. Also includes handwritten and typed field notes along with handwritten transcripts. Tapia's exhibit is also includes along with color prints of his art work.
    - Luis Tapia, August 2, 1984, AFC 2022/001: SR08; Santo maker; 1 sound cassette
      Luis Tapia is a Santo maker from Santa Fe, New Mexico.
    - Luis Tapia, February 22, 1986, AFC 2022/001: SR09; Santo maker; 1 sound cassette
    - Luis Tapia, 1990, AFC 2022/001: PH05-21; 1 color slide (35 mm) (Box 11)
      Notes from original housing: Luis Tapia ca, 1990 musicians (Flaco Jimenez?).
    - Luis Tapia, 1990, AFC 2022/001: PH05-22; 1 color slide (35 mm) (Box 11)
      Notes from original housing: Luis Tapia, N.S. de Guade ca., 1990.
    - Antonio and Andy Trujillo, August 23, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR11; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Antonio and Andy Trujillo Mosquero, New Mexico. Interviewed by (BCP and LK).
    - Erma Trujillo in Erma's café, August 22, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR20; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Copy-NM85-LK2.
    - Erma Trujillo, August 22, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR19; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Copy NM85-LKA 1.
    - Charles "Chuck" Payne and Linda Leak, August 28, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR21; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: NM85-LKA3 Interview with Charles "Chuck" Payne and Linda Leak at the Five State Livestock Auction Co. Inc., Clayton, New Mexico.
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr12.
    - Lloyd and Irene Tower, August 28, 1985, AFC 2022/001: SR22; 1 sound cassette
      Notes from original housing: Copy-NM85-LK4.
      This interview is also represented in the New Mexico Folklife Project collection, afc1991032_sr13.
    - Individual artist, AFC 2022/001: PH05-01 — PH05-32; 30 color slides (35 mm); 2 black-and-white slides (35 mm) (Box 11)
      Notes from original housing: 001-020: not labeled; 021-022: see Series 1, Tapia; 023-024: not labeled; 025: Pear wood, Santa Fe, Estella Cismenos mode, "I could be dancing all night;" 026-027: black-and-white slides (35 mm); 028: unlabeled item; 029: "Pajarito" sold; 030: Coming of Christ, 20x 21x 9, wood, 1989? $3000; 031: 1989 pine, trade w/ Rudy Fernandez; 032: 1989.
  - Subseries 2: Field photography of New Mexico Santos, 1983-1990
    - Slides by Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo, AFC 2022/001: PH01-001 — PH01-192; 192 color slides (35 mm) (Box 6)
      Notes from original housing: Slides by Laurie Kalb Cosmo. Some dupes of AFC slides by Carl Fleischhauer.
    - Slides by Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo, AFC 2022/001: PH01-193, PH01-309, PH01-311 — PH01-337, PH01-340 — PH01-344, PH01-346 — PH01-359, PH01-361 — PH01-388; 190 color slides (35 mm) (Box 7)
      Notes from original housing: Slides by Laurie Kalb Cosmo. Some may be duplicates of AFC slides from The New Mexico Folklife Project. Some dupes of AFC slides by Carl Fleischhauer.
    - Slides by Laurie Beth Kalb Cosmo, AFC 2022/001: PH01-310, PH01-338 — PH01-339, PH01-345, PH01-360; 5 color slide (35mm) (Box 14)
    - Spanish colonial santos, 1984-04, April 1984; AFC 2022/001: PH01-525 — PH01-551; 27 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
      AFC 2022/001: PH01-525—PH01-551: Spanish Colonial Santos from Smithsonian Collection Museum of Nature History.
    - Ortega Gallery, 1983, AFC 2022/001: PH01-552 — PH01-573; 22 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
      Notes from original housing: Santa Fe Chimayo - Ortega Gallery.
    - Field photography of the installation of santos, 1983-1990, AFC 2022/001: PH01-574 — PH01-577; 4 color transparency film (4x5) (Box 3)
  - Subseries 3: Field photography of Cultural Preservation Project
    - New Mexico Santeros; Shrine of Kateri Tekakwitha, 1984, AFC 2022/001: PH02-001 — PH02-089; 89 color slides (35 mm) (Box 8)
    - Cultural Conservation Project, NE Sector Overview, 1985, AFC 2022/001: PH02-090 — PH02-185; 95 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
    - New Mexico, summer, 1983, AFC 2022/001: PH02-186 — PH02-199; 14 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
    - New Mexico, 1983, AFC 2022/001: PH02-200 — PH02-221; 21 color slides (35 mm) (Box 9)
  - Subseries 4: Field notes and photography of Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1983-1984, 1986 and Spanish market, 1986
    - Spanish market, 1986, AFC 2022/001: PH03-001 — PH03-093; 93 color slides (35 mm) (Box 10)
    - Summer fieldwork, October 18, 1983, manuscript materials and 5 black-and-white prints (3 1/2 x 5) (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Summer fieldwork, November 22, 1983, 21 black-and-white prints (3 1/2 x 5) (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Summer fieldwork, April 23, 1984 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Summer fieldwork, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 2/28)
      Folder also includes photo envelopes from camera shop.
    - Items found with photographic materials, undated (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Slides index, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Santa Fe, New Mexico, AFC 2022/001: PH03; 1 head leader (Box 4)
    - Summer, 1983, AFC 2022/001: PH03; 1 head leader; 5 color negative strips (12 frames) (Box 4)
      Contains a leader and unlabeled item content. Each of the 5 strips has 2 frames each.
    - Folk Art Music, August 30, 1983, AFC 2022/001: PH03; 6 black-and-white negative strips (36 frames) (Box 5)
    - Unlabeled item, October 18, 1983, AFC 2022/001: PH03; 6 black-and-white negative strips (35 frames) (Box 5)
    - Unlabeled item, December 14, 1983, AFC 2022/001: PH03; 6 black-and-white negative strips (36 frames) (Box 5)
    - Unlabeled item, April 23, 1984, AFC 2022/001: PH03; 4 black-and-white negative strips (23 frames) (Box 5)
      See 2/27 for associated black-and-white prints.
    - Unlabeled item, July 1, AFC 2022/001: PH03; 6 black-and-white negative strips (37 frames) (Box 5)
    - Unlabeled item, September 30, AFC 2022/001: PH03; 3 black-and-white negative strips (36 frames) (Box 5)
  - Subseries 5: Various field photography, Deborah Flynn photos of 84 Spanish market, Santos. 83, Velarde, New Mexico, Enrique, Actual box: summer '84 E.R.'s images, St. Francis, St. Teresa, St. Matin's E.R. backyard.
    - An assortment of art and various cultural activities in New Mexico, 1983-1998, AFC 2022/001: PH07-01PH07-100; 100 color slides (35 mm) (Box 12)
      Notes from original housing: 01: Spanish market: St. Francis, St. Ramen, photo by D. Flynn (1984); 02: Spanish market: Photo by D. Flynn by Horacio Valdez (1984); 03: Eurgencio Lopez, Cordova, New Mexico; 04: Crosses on a red background; 05: Lady at table with the red crosses; 06: [Skeleton in a box]-title supplied by archivist; 07: Fred Vigil, center of alter, St. John's Church, Santa Fe; 08: Fredrico Vigil, St. John's Church, Santa Fe; 09: Fred Vigil, St. John's Church, Santa Fe; 10: Fred Vigil, St. John's Church, bottom left of alter; 11: Gloria Lopez Cordola, Feria Artesana, Albuquerque, (1983); 12: Feria Artesana, Albuquerque, (1983); 13: Fred Vigil, bottom left of altar, St. John's Church, Sante Fe; 14: Fred Vigil, top left of alter, St. John's Church, Santa Fe; 15: Fred Vigil, center of alter, St. John's Church, Santa Fe; 16: Eurgencio Lopez, Cordova, New Mexico; 17: Statue of the Virgin Mary; 18: Male in blue shirt; 19-30: unlabeled item; 31: Spanish market (1984); 32: Canyon de Mosquero, Pachecos Place; 33: unlabeled item; 34: Canyon de Mosquero, stone house at end of canyon; 35: Canyon de Mosquero, stone house at end of canyon; 36: Canyon de Mosquero, Jacal; 37: Digital content available, NM85 CF3 -7: Bill Wright, auctioneer and described as co-owner livestock auction; 38: unlabeled item; 39: Labor Day rodeo, serving barbeque, Hayden, New Mexico (1985); 40: Labor Day rodeo Hayden cowboy club members serving barbeque, Hayden, New Mexico (1985); 41: Hayden, New Mexico (1985); 42: Hayden, New Mexico (1985); 43: Parking '87, Hayden, New Mexico (1987); 44: Labor Day rodeo, Hayden, New Mexico, 1985; 45: Canyon de Mosquero for hanging animal, place at end of canyon; 46: Canyon de Mosquero, Image of Jacal Margarito Garcia; 47: Canyon de Mosquero, Cartwheel, Pacheco's Place; 48: Alessandra Cordova and Joe Cordova, grandchildren, and interview, Mosquero, New Mexico, NM85-CF-9 (August 29, 1985); 49: Mosquero, New Mexico, Antonio Trujillo and Brad Pitt on bench in front of general store (August 21-22, 1985); 50: The bench at Trujillo's store, scenes in town, interview with Margarito and Trinidad Garcia, Mosquero, New Mexico, M85-CF-14-3; 51: St. Joseph's Roman Catholic Church, building and grounds, scenes of the town, Mosquero, New Mexico, NM85-CF13-15 (August 30, 1985); 52: Ledeux Graveadorened with painted cinder blocks, Santa Clara cemetery, Wagon Mound; 53: Garcia ranch, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico, NM85-CF17-5, ( August 30-31, 1985); 54: Egg carton vase, Santa Clara cemetery, Wagon mound, New Mexico; 55: Santa Clara cemetery, wagon mound, New Mexico, (Aug 21, 1985); 56: Fraker Gravestone, Santa Clara, Wagon Mound, New Mexico (1997); 57: Fraker Family plot, Santa Clara cemetery, Wagon Mound, New Mexico (1998); 58: Houses from Dawson coal mine company town, Lloyd Tower and Irene Tower, Clayton, New Mexico, NM85-CF5-12 (August 28, 1985); 59: Houses from Dawson coal mine company town, Lloyd Tower and Irene Tower, Clayton, New Mexico, NM85-CF5-14( August 28, 1985); 60: Dawson worker's house, Clayton, New Mexico; 61: Dawson worker's house, Clayton, New Mexico; 62: Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico; Houses from Dawson coal mine company town, Clayton, New Mexico NM85-CF4-2, (August 28, 1985); 63: Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico NM85-CF3-12, (August 28, 1985); 64: Livestock auction, Clayton, New Mexico; 65-66: unlabeled item; 67: Catholic Church of the Immaculate Conception, Gallegos, New Mexico, Photo by Boyd Pratt; 68: Photo by Boyd Pratt; 69: Outside of Johnson log cabin, Horizontal construction with poor notching (August 9, 1985); 70: Santiago Apstoic Church, Maes, New Mexico (August 13, 1985); 71: 2- story barn, Maes, New Mexico, Photo by Boyd Pratt, Maes, New Mexico; 72: Enrique Rendon, San Francisco recent additions, Velarde, New Mexico 00147; 73: [Wooden statue of Jesus?]; 74: Felipe Archuleta, Tesuque, New Mexico; 75: ER retablo, Velarde, New Mexico; 76: [2 wooden statues]; 77: Felipe Archuleta, Tesuque, New Mexico; 78: Unlabelled item, 79: Enrique Rendon, Velarde N.M. 1986, Guadelupe y Juan Diego (1986); 80: Luis Tapia, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1883-1984, San Miguel, Our Lady of Sorrows, San Pedro Apostol (1983-1984); 81: China section of Moa, New Mexico interior of church, photo by LBK, 1984; 82: [Altar of religious statues]; 83: Velarde, New Mexico, 1sr visit (1984), E.R. Cristo; 84: Heads for Enrique's santos, Velarde, New Mexico; 85: E.R. San Antonio's Velarde; 86: Velarde, E.R. San Antonio's; 87: Velarde, muerte, ER; 88: Velarde, muerto, ER; 89: Velarde, muerto, ER; 90: Donkey made for bought cart, Velarde, New Mexico; 91: Donkey made for bought cart, Velarde, New Mexico; 92: Velarde, ER, San Antonio (1976); 93: Wood for drums made at Red skirt /indian drum shop, Taos, New Mexico; 94: Velarde, ER, San Antonio (1976); 95: Velarde, ER, San Antonio (1986); 96: Velarde, E.R. Santa Bernadette; 97: Bows for E.R.'s santos, Velarde; 98: Bows for ER's santos, Velarde; 99: Lamb by Felipe Archuletta, Owned by Gere Kavanaugh; 100: ER St. Jude, Velarde.
    - Unidentified project, AFC 2022/001: PH07; 4 color negative strips (7 frames) (Box 4)
      Contains unlabeled item content. Each strip was cut so they do not have the normal amount of frames. Each of the strips contains 2 frames and 1 strip contains 1 frame.
    - Summer, 1984, AFC 2022/001: PH07; 3 color negative strips (5 frames) (Box 4)
      The following names were recorded as being associated to the negatives. E.R images, St. Francis, St. Teresa, St. Martin and ER's background. Each strip was cut so they do not have the normal amount of frames. Each of the strips contains 2 frames and 1 strip contains 1 frame.
- Series 2: Exhibitions
  - Subseries 1: Santos Statues and Sculpture: Contemporary Woodcarving from New Mexico 1988
    - Santos Statues and Sculpture: Contemporary Woodcarving in New Mexico, catalogue and research materials, 1984-1988 (1/2), 1984-1988 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Santos Statues and Sculpture: Contemporary Woodcarving in New Mexico, catalogue and research materials, 1984-1988 (2/2), 1988, 1 color transparency; 2 black and white (4x6); 1 black-and-white print (5x7); 10 black-and-white prints (Box-folder 2/2)
      Includes correspondence and photographic prints.
    - Santos, Statues and Sculpture Contemporary woodcarving from New Mexico, CAFAM, LA, 1988, prints, 1988, 1 black-and-white print (Box-folder 2/3)
      Includes 7 black-and-white photocopied prints and 1 photo print of various artist and their artwork.
    - Correspondence with Santeros community and Ortega, 1991, 1996 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Subseries 2: Crafting Devotions: Tradition in Contemporary, New Mexico Santos, 1976-1995
    - Notes and correspondence